

Derek SEVERINSoftware Engineer

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam ↑
severinderek@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/DerekSeverin in

+84 120 200 56 47 📞

Date of Birth: 22 / 11 / 1979 📅

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Software design (UX / UI, CAD tools, 3D simulators, media players, web, ...)
- Video games
- 2D / 3D conception (graphic design & CAD)
- Embedded systems (Android, Linux, ...)

SKILLS

- Programming (Java, C, C++, ...)
- Team and project management
- Game design (Unity, GameMaker, 3DSMAX, Blender, Photoshop)
- Versatility
- Quick learning and adaptability

HOBBIES / INTERESTS

- Video games (play and design)
- Music (drums, guitar, DAW)
- Sport (football, basketball)
- Traveling

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent
French: Native
Spanish: Intermediate
Dutch: Basic

Dual British / Citizenship: Belgian

REFERENCES

Available on request.

PROFILE

Software engineer with 12+ years' experience in various positions and industries. As a consultant, have developed over the years the ability to easily adapt to new environments and technologies, being always eager to learn and face new challenges. Able to work autonomously or as part of a team, and experienced in collaborating with several teams and departments simultaneously. Looking for projects on which I can develop and share my technical and management skills.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2014 - Embedded C IKM Assessment - Score of 86%

2012 - C++ IKM Assessment - Score of 97%

2003 – Master in Computer Sciences – Université Libre de Bruxelles (ULB)

Thesis subject: "Digital Images Indexing on 3D Models"

1997 - European Baccalaureate - European School of Brussels 2

WORK EXPERIENCE

AKKA Belgium | IT Consultant & Project Manager

Mar 2012 - Jan 2018

AGC (AKKA Consultant) | Functional Analyst

Aug 2017 - Jan 2018

As part of the Information Flow Management team in the Supply Chain department, responsible for establishing new EDI relationships with suppliers and maintaining existing ones with clients, acting as the point of contact between the business partners and technical teams.

Gathering, analysis and communication of business requirements and functional specifications, and follow-up of the project's development to make sure business goals are met.

Identification and troubleshooting of EDI production issues as they arise, and coordination with the appropriate service or partner to determine source of problems and possible resolutions.

Technologies / Tools:

EDI (EDIFACT, VDA), IDoc, Log2000 / Novation, SAP

TOYOTA MOTOR EUROPE (AKKA Consultant) | Team Leader Dec 2016 - Sep 2017

Technical leader for the DCT project consisting in a complete software solution to greatly streamline the drawing comparison process currently done manually by engineers.

Leader of the development team, responsible for the technical aspects required to successfully realise the solution according to the client's requirements: an efficient, robust and scalable system combining low level image analysis algorithms with high level web and distributed technologies.

Technologies / Tools:

Scrum, JIRA, MS Project, JavaScript, React, Redux, Pixi.js, OpenCV, Node.js, IntelliJ, Git

AKKA Belgium (Internal project) | Project Leader

Jul 2016 - Sep 2016

Project leader for the development of a proof of concept tool to automatically compare two revisions of a technical drawing and highlight the differences between them.

Responsible for the management of the development team and for the redaction of the feasibility study document, used to convince Toyota Motor Europe to choose our company to develop the full scale final system.

Technologies / Tools: MS Project, C++, Qt, OpenCV, Visual Studio, Qt Creator

INFRABEL s.a. (AKKA Consultant) | Software Engineer

Nov 2014 - Jun 2016

Part of the development team on the IFAST project, consisting in the development of a tablet application to digitise and partly automate the process of railway shelter field-testing, greatly increasing the workers productivity. Mostly in charge of the user interface and the digital test sheets generation and management.

Technologies / Tools: Java, JavaFX, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, NetBeans, Oxygen, JIRA, Mantisse, Windows tablet

AKKA Belgium (Internal project) | Project Leader

Jul 2014 - Oct 2014

Project leader for the development of a prototype to automatically detect and extract elements in 2D plans by using image recognition techniques, applied to the railway sector. Successful realisation and demonstration of the prototype enabling the development team to be chosen for a larger scale project at Infrabel.

Technologies / Tools: Java, Swing, OpenCV, NetBeans

SONACA s.a. (Intern & AKKA Consultant) | CAD Software Engineer

Jul 2007 - Oct 2010 & Feb 2013 - Jun 2014

Responsible for the development and maintenance of internally developed CATIA V5 modules (plugins and batch applications) assisting and validating the designers work. Creation of data conversion and archiving tools interacting with the different PLM systems automating data exchanges with clients. Level 2 and 3 support on data exchange procedures and CATIA V5 tools.

Proposition and implementation of an automated commands and tools development framework for CATIA V5 built on top of the CAA API greatly accelerating internal developments.

Technologies / Tools: C++, CAA RADE, C#, VB.NET, SQL, shell script, Visual Studio, CATIA V5, VPM, UNIX

ATOS WORLDLINE (AKKA Consultant) | Embedded Software Engineer

Apr 2012 – Jan 2013

Development of embedded software on payment terminals extending their functionalities and providing a better user experience (gas and electricity top-up management, survey and advertisement tools).

Responsible for the coordination between the different teams and departments in Brussels and Luxembourg, in order to validate and present the final products to the management and clients.

Technologies / Tools: C, Python, XML, Agile, Eclipse, GCC, XENTA & YOMANI payment terminals

MULTITEL a.s.b.l. | Research Engineer

Mar 2004 - Jun 2007

Design, development and integration of tailor-made video, 3D and virtual reality software solutions for various clients in the security and medical industries, extending the scope of the company's activities.

In charge of decision-making and setting up of real-time video streaming concepts and technologies proposed to partners for the good realisation of European FP6 R&D projects.

Technologies / Tools: C, C++, Java, Visual Studio, Blender, Gimp, Ogre 3D, OpenGL, ffmpeg, DirectShow, Windows CE

VR CONTEXT s.a. | 3D Modeller and Tools Developer

Oct 2003 - Jan 2004

Creation of 3D animated human characters in 3DSMAX and development of a file exporter plugin allowing the models to be used in the company's virtual reality security simulation software.

Technologies / Tools: C++, MAXSCRIPT, 3DSMAX, Photoshop, Visual Studio